

PRIYANKA MUKHERJEE

priyanka.mukherjee623@gmail.com | 7200258691

Websites, Portfolios, Profiles

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/priyanka-mukherjee
- https://mukherjeecodes.com/
- https://github.com/fortheloveofcode1

Summary

Dedicated Consultant bringing dynamic skills in client oversight, issue resolution and presentation. Successful juggling multiple tasks and projects simultaneously. Excellent business knowledge within Banking industry with experience with application dealing with International Trade, Securities, Card processing.

Skills

- Cobol
- Db2
- Rexx
- Vsam
- Java
- XML

- Python
- CICS
- Technical Review
- Team Leadership
- Securities Trading

Experience

Volvo | Bengalore **Consultant** 01/2023 - 03/2024

Societe Generale | Bengalore, India Technical Lead 10/2021 - 12/2022

Fidelity Investments | Bengalore **Technical Lead** 06/2018 - 10/2021

- Leading a team of 5 developers in analyzing and optimizing a legacy system, resulting in a 30% reduction in operational costs and elimination of 50+ redundant and unused functions.
- Facilitated workshops with cross-functional teams to review current practices related to innovation and growth opportunities.
- Orchestrated a team of 10 developers to successfully create and launch a new age mainframe application, revolutionizing the India product portfolio of Société Générale; resulted in a 40% increase in user engagement and a 25% boost in revenue.
- Mentored junior developers on coding best practices and standards.
- Created detailed project plans with timelines, deliverables, and resources needed.
- Developed and maintained technical documentation for the application.
- Led multiple client-specific projects, enhancing data integrity in the Workplace Investment domain by implementing data validation rules, resulting in a 30% reduction in data inconsistencies.
- Collaborated with other team members to troubleshoot complex issues and develop solutions.
- Performed root cause analysis for production incidents and identified permanent fixes.

Infosys **Technical Lead**02/2017 - 06/2018

Cognizant | Chennai **Associate** 08/2013 - 06/2017

- A team of 6 for the enhancement and development work under member domain (for an Insurance Company) for a system called DataMigrator
- Key developer for an application called Overpayment Tracking System (claims domain).
- One of the Key developers in APM (alternate Payment Method) which was a product of one of the reputed Debit/Credit card processing company, which managed the backend processing of all the transaction that are not through Debit/Credit card
- Key developer in the migration (from Assembler to Cobol)project
- Led the initiative of gathering problem statements from various teams and developed a user-friendly tool using Rexx and Excel Macro; enhanced collaboration and streamlined problem-solving efforts, resulting in a 15% increase in customer satisfaction.

Education and Training

Future Institute of Engineering & Management Bachelor of Technology (dept. IT, final year) 06/2013 CGPA: 8.00

Navyug Vidhyalaya **AISSCE** 05/2009 CGPA: 85.4

St. Teresa's School ICSE 05/2007 CGPA: 83.43

Accomplishments

- Spot Award 2023 in Volvo
- Spot Award 2022 in Société Générale
- Best team Award in 2020 (Fidelity)
- Green mile Award in Q3 2018 (Fidelity)
- Achieved All India Rank 7 in the prestigious Techgig Greek Goddess Code Competition in 2017; outperformed 5,000+
 participants by developing an innovative algorithm that optimized data processing speed by 40% and reduced
 computational time by 50%.
- Got Star award in Q2 2015(Cognizant)

Certifications

• Foundation in Data Science from IIT Madras